Guide to the Joseph L. Fisher papers, 1930s-1992
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections Research Center
- Series 2: Academic Career/Government Appointments, 1930s-1992
  - Economic development and environmental protection: Technology and public policy by Fisher in Professional Engineer, August 1972 (Box 98, Folder 3)
  - Future energy demand and its effects on the environment, September 1972 (Box 98, Folder 4)
  - Epilogue to "The No-Growth Society," by Fisher in Daedalus, Fall 1973 (Box 98, Folder 5)
  - Statement by Fisher in the Proceedings of the Western Governor's conference, September 22-26, 1973 (Box 98, Folder 6)
  - El problema de los recursos no renovables by Fisher in Atalaya, 1974 (Box 98, Folder 7)
  - A search for consensus by Fisher in Forest Policy for the Future, June 1974 (Box 98, Folder 8)
  - A personal reminiscence by Fisher for Edwin Griswold Nourse memorial service, 1975 (Box 98, Folder 9)
  - Non-renewable natural resource availability by Fisher in Perspectives in Natural Resource Management, January 1975 (Box 98, Folder 10)
  - Energy choices and public policy by Fisher in Journal of the Air Pollution Control Association, September 1975 (Box 98, Folder 11)
  - The effects of population growth on resource adequacy and quality by Fisher and Neal Potter, includes revisions, 1974-1975 (Box 98, Folder 12)
  - Resources for the future, the first 25 years, 1977 (Box 98, Folder 13)
  - Perspectives on the Unitarian Universalist future by Fisher in Unitarian Universalist World, April 15, 1977 (Box 99, Folder 1)
  - Key note address - The importance of the built environment to the quality of American life, 1980 (Box 99, Folder 2)
  - Preserving the Potomac by Fisher in Environmental Protection Agency Journal, June 1979 (Box 99, Folder 3)
  - Perspective from public interest groups by Fisher in Policy Issues, 1982 (Box 99, Folder 4)
  - Energy policy in perspective - solutions, problems, and prospects, symposium proceedings, 1982 (Box 99, Folder 5)
  - Human services in a time of diminished resources by Fisher, May 1983 (Box 99, Folder 6)
  - Our groundwater is generally good by Fisher in Virginia's Groundwater - symposium proceedings, November 9-10, 1983 (Box 99, Folder 7)
  - The future of Arlington: The year 2000 and beyond, November 1986 (Box 99, Folder 8)
  - Virginia alternatives for the 1990s edited by Fisher and Richard T. Mayer, 1987 (Box 99, Folder 9)
  - On umbrella's and human services in Virginia, 1988 (Box 99, Folder 10)
  - The future of Northern Virginia: Challenge and realization by Fisher in Northern Virginia Challenges: The 1990s and Beyond edited by Fisher and Richard T. Mayer, 1989 (Box 99, Folder 11)
  - Toward a Northern Virginia style by Fisher in New Dominion, July - August 1989 (Box 99, Folder 12)
  - Formal mechanisms: Helping the Governor to manage by Fisher in The Journal of State Government, July - August 1989 (Box 99, Folder 13)
  - Beyond distrust: Building bridges between congress and the executive, January 1992 (Box 99, Folder 14)
  - Scrapbook: World War II, photocopies, 1940s (Box 99, Folder 15)
  - Scrapbook: Build up to primary, photocopies, 1972-1974 (Box 100, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook, photocopies, June 13, 1974 - November 6, 1974 (Box 100, Folder 2)
  - Scrapbook, photocopies, November 6, 1974 - February 14, 1975 (Box 100, Folder 3)
  - Scrapbook, photocopies, 1975 (Box 100, Folder 4)
  - Scrapbook, photocopies, 1975 (Box 100, Folder 5)
  - Scrapbook, photocopies, 1975-1976 (Box 100, Folder 6)
  - Scrapbook, photocopies, November 1976 - May 1977 (Box 100, Folder 7)
  - Scrapbook, photocopies, 1977-1978 (Box 100, Folder 8)
  - Scrapbook, photocopies, June 1978 - January 1979 (Box 100, Folder 9)
  - Scrapbook, photocopies, 1979 (Box 101, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook, photocopies, November 1979 - August 1980 (Box 101, Folder 2)
  - Scrapbook, photocopies, September - December 1980 (Box 101, Folder 3)
  - Scrapbook, photocopies, January 1981 - January 1982 (Box 101, Folder 4)
  - Scrapbook, photocopies, 1982 (Box 101, Folder 5)
  - Scrapbook, 1975-1976 (Box 114, Folder 1)
    Newspaper and magazine clippings, photographs, invitations, newsletters, letters from the White House, removed from a scrapbook.
  - Scrapbook (1 of 2), 1975 (Box 114, Folder 2)
  - Scrapbook (2 of 2), 1975 (Box 114, Folder 3)
    Newspaper and magazine clippings, photographs, invitations, newsletters, letters from the White House, and photographs removed from a scrapbook.
  - Class photograph, photocopy, undated (Box 101, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous photocopies, newspaper clipping, June 12, 1983 (Box 101, Folder 7)
  - Memorial service program and speech by David Potter for Fisher, 1992 (Box 101, Folder 8)
  - Paper: Planning through cost accounting and budgetary control, circa 1940s (Box 102, Folder 1)
  - Paper: Economic planning among private enterprises, 1940s (Box 102, Folder 2)
  - Paper: Economic planning in semi-private industry, circa 1940s (Box 102, Folder 3)
  - Paper: Regional planning and the T.V.A., circa 1940s (Box 102, Folder 4)
  - Paper: Federal planning of public works, circa 1940s (Box 102, Folder 5)
  - Paper: Budgetary planning in the federal government, circa 1940s (Box 102, Folder 6)
  - Paper: Economic planning - government financial planning, circa 1940s (Box 102, Folder 7)
  - Paper: Economic and social planning in the U.S.S.R., circa 1940s (Box 102, Folder 8)
  - Paper: A case study of private industrial planning, circa 1940s (Box 102, Folder 9)
  - Paper: A summary of economic planning, May 22, 1940 (Box 102, Folder 10)
  - Paper: Planning in personnel relations, circa 1940s (Box 102, Folder 11)
  - National industrial conference board, inc., notes and newspaper clipping, 1940 (Box 102, Folder 12)
  - Economic analysis, handwritten notes, 1940 (Box 102, Folder 13)
  - Advanced economics, handwritten notes, 1930s (Box 102, Folder 14)
  - Distribution of income, handwritten notes, 1936 (Box 102, Folder 15)
  - Theory of production, handwritten notes, 1930s (Box 102, Folder 16)
  - Programming the public works of the federal government by Robert W. Hartley, 1930s-1940s (Box 102, Folder 17)
  - Natural resources, 1940s-1952 (Box 102, Folder 18)
  - Business cycles, handwritten notes, 1939 (Box 102, Folder 19)
  - Industrial fluctuations, handwritten notes, 1930s (Box 102, Folder 20)
  - University of Alaska (submission for employment), April 30, 1953 (Box 102, Folder 21)
  - University of Alaska (submission for employment), April 30, 1953 (Box 102, File 22)
  - University of Alaska (submission for employment), April 30, 1953 (Box 103, Folder 1)
  - University of Alaska (submission for employment), correspondence, 1949-1953 (Box 103, Folder 2)
  - Resource education, United Nations economic and social council, 1949 (Box 103, Folder 3)
  - General, 1945-1950 (Box 103, Folder 4)
  - Article citations, handwritten notes, circa 1940s-1950s (Box 103, Folder 5)
  - School papers with edits, circa 1930s-1940s (Box 103, Folder 6)
  - Dissertation research, 1940s (Box 103, Folder 7)
  - Paper with edits, dissertation, circa 1930s-1940s (Box 103, Folder 8)
  - Resources conservation and development, 1951 (Box 103, Folder 9)
  - Conservation education, 1938-1951 (Box 103, Folder 10)
  - Conservation education, 1951 (Box 103, Folder 11)
  - Note cards for thesis, circa 1930s-1940s (Box 103, Folder 12)
  - Education: George Washington University, class notes, papers, 1950 (Box 103, Folder 13)
  - George Washington University education, 1950s (Box 104, Folder 1)
  - Writings on education, 1940s (Box 104, Folder 2)
  - Adult education, YMCA, 1940s (Box 104, Folder 3)
  - Bibliography and public documents citations, circa 1940s (Box 104, Folder 4)
  - Thesis, 1951 (Box 104, Folder 5)
  - Education, 1949 (Box 104, Folder 6)
  - National planning association, 1952 (Box 104, Folder 7)
  - Social science survey, 1939-1940 (Box 104, Folder 8)
  - Social science survey, 1938-1939 (Box 104, Folder 9)
  - Public policy papers, 1948-1949 (Box 105, Folder 1)
  - The American foreign service, 1937-1940 (Box 105, Folder 2)
  - School facilities survey, 1952 (Box 105, Folder 3)
  - College building needs, 1940s (Box 105, Folder 4)
  - Citizens look at our school houses, November 1950 (Box 105, Folder 5)
  - School facilities survey, 1953 (Box 105, Folder 6)
  - A regional development plan for the region composed of the states of Indiana, Illinois, Kentucky, Michigan, Ohio, West Virginia, and Wisconsin, 1940 (Box 105, Folder 7)
  - Office of education, 1951-1952 (Box 105, Folder 8)
  - Office of education, 1951 (Box 105, Folder 9)
  - Bowdoin College, handwritten notes, Sociology, 1940s (Box 105, Folder 10)
  - An introduction to social science, 1939-1940 (Box 105, Folder 11)
  - A joint criticism of economics fourteen Allegheny College, 1940 (Box 105, Folder 12)
  - Alaska and Hawaii, 1946-1947 (Box 106, Folder 8)
  - The external trade of the Pacific Northwest, 1942 (Box 106, Folder 9)
  - Forestry, 1943-1945 (Box 106, Folder 10)
  - Alaska photostats, 1940s (Box 106, Folder 11)
  - External trade of Alaska, 1931-1940 by Fisher, 1943 (Box 106, Folder 12)
  - Securities, bonds, and receipts, 1940s (Box 106, Folder 13)
  - Thesis, original copy, 1946 (Box 106, Folder 14)
  - Thesis, original copy, 1946 (Box 107, Folder 1)
  - Thesis, original copy, 1946 (Box 107, Folder 2)
  - Alaska, 1949 (Box 107, Folder 3)
  - Alaska, 1948-1949 (Box 107, Folder 4)
  - Alaska, file no. 3, 1950 (Box 107, Folder 5)
  - Alaska, file no. 3, 1952 (Box 107, Folder 6)
  - Bowdoin College congratulatory letter, June 26, 1934 (Box 107, Folder 7)
  - Personal items, 1943-1947 (Box 107, Folder 8)
  - Personal and business correspondence, 1940-1946 (Box 107, Folder 9)
  - American economic review, December 2, 1948 (Box 107, Folder 10)
  - The role of the federal government in the operation of the American economic system, July 1952 (Box 108, Folder 1)
  - Natural resources and technological change, February 1953 (Box 108, Folder 2)
  - Regional-urban relationships from the viewpoint of the region, March 20, 1951 (Box 108, Folder 3)
  - Natural resources and technological change, February 1953 (Box 108, Folder 4)
  - Notes from W.C. Mitchell and Epstein's Business Cycles and Industrial Profits in the U.S., circa 1940s (Box 108, Folder 5)
  - The allocation of joint costs of multiple purpose projects, August 29, 1939 (Box 108, Folder 6)
  - Academic papers and notes, 1948 (Box 108, Folder 7)
  - Harvard University papers, 1937-1938 (Box 108, Folder 8)
  - Class notes, newspaper clippings, 1930s (Box 108, Folder 9)
  - International economics theory, circa 1930s-1950s (Box 108, Folder 10)
  - Structure of modern industry, notes, circa 1930s-1950s (Box 108, Folder 11)
  - Reviews, notes, 1930s (Box 108, Folder 12)
  - Philosophy I class notes, 1930s (Box 108, Folder 13)
  - Philosophy 5: Present developments in metaphysics at Bowdoin, class notes, 1935-1936 (Box 108, Folder 14)
  - Economics I, class notes, 1939-1940 (Box 108, Folder 15)
  - Economics I, class notes, 1934 (Box 108, Folder 16)
  - Economics 13, Babson's reports, 1938-1939 (Box 109, Folder 1)
  - General theory economics 101, Professor Schumpeter, Harvard, 1936-1937 (Box 109, Folder 2)
  - Economic theory professor O.H. Taylor, Harvard, 1937-1938 (Box 109, Folder 3)
  - Principles of money and banking, economics 141, Professor Williams, Harvard, 1936-1937 (Box 109, Folder 4)
  - Economics 145A, business cycle, Harvard, 1930s (Box 109, Folder 5)
  - Labor problems, newspaper clippings, notes, 1938-1940 (Box 109, Folder 6)
  - Labor problems, EC181, Professor Slichter, Harvard, 1936-1937 (Box 109, Folder 7)
  - Time series, notes, circa 1930s-1940s (Box 109, Folder 8)
  - Statistics, economics, 1936-1940 (Box 109, Folder 9)
  - Recent economic history EC133, Professor Usher, Harvard, 1936-1937 (Box 109, Folder 10)
  - Economics 13, 1930s (Box 109, Folder 11)
  - Classical economics, 1930s (Box 109, Folder 12)
  - Economics 21A, class notes, 1936 (Box 109, Folder 13)
  - Economics 102A, class notes, 1930s (Box 109, Folder 14)
  - Economics 121A, statistical theory and analysis, class notes, 1937-1938 (Box 109, Folder 15)
  - Class notes for Economics 121B - Theory of economic statistics II, 1936-1937 (Box 110, Folder 1)
  - Class notes for Economics 143 with Professor Haberler, 1937 (Box 110, Folder 2)
  - Class notes for International Trade and Economics, 1938-1940 (Box 110, Folder 3)
  - Class notes for Economics 9, 1938-1939 (Box 110, Folder 4)
  - United States Army Stars and Stripes editorials by Fisher, 1945-1946 (Box 110, Folder 5)
  - Problems and possibilities for Canadian-American collaboration in the North Pacific area, 1942-1943 (Box 110, Folder 6)
- Series 3: Oversize, 1943-1992
  This series consists of two flat boxes that contain awards, certificates, and diplomas for both Joseph and Margaret Fisher, as well as campaign posters, a large newspaper clipping, a large photograph, and scrapbook covers.
  - Awards, certificates, photograph, diplomas, 1951-1991 (Box 115, Folder 1)
  - Campaign posters, 1970s (Box 115)
  - Commonwealth of Virginia General Assembly House Joint Resolution No. 352 on the death of Joseph L. Fisher, February 1992 (Box 115)
  - The International Public Official Award, October 4, 1991 (Box 116)
  - Key to the city of Fairfax, July 4, 1979 (Box 116)
  - Margaret Fisher awards, certificates, diplomas, 1943-1991 (Box 115, Folder 2)
  - Newspaper clipping mounted to board, June 12, 1983 (Box 115)
  - Scrapbook covers, February 1975 (Box 115)
  - American Forestry Association, life member certificate, October 22, 1984 (Box 116)